stampready.net 2018-11-23

# StampReady - Privacy Policy

StampReady Privacy Policy 

We at StampReady value the right to privacy. In order to protect your right to online privacy we have established this Privacy Policy which explains how we collect, use, disclose, and protect the information we collect when you visit our website or that applies to our Services. This Privacy Policy applies exclusively to [www.stampready.net](http://www.stampready.net/) (“Website”).

Please read this Privacy Policy, our [Terms and Conditions](http://www.stampready.net/terms/terms-and-conditions/) and [Cookie Policy](http://www.stampready.net/terms/cookie-policy/) (together referred to as “Terms”) carefully before accessing or using the website, [www.stampready.net](http://www.stampready.net/) (“Website”) and the Services.

By accessing or using the Website and the Services you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions set forth in our Terms. By using StampReady or signing up for an account, you are agreeing to these Terms. This is a legal agreement. If you do not wish to be bound by these terms and conditions, you may not access or use the Website and the Services and you should immediately end such use.

Capitalized terms that are not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meaning given to them in our Terms and Conditions.

If you have any questions about our Terms, please do not hesitate to [contact us](mailto:terms@stampready.net).

## 1\. Definitions

### 1.1

“us” or “we” or “our” or “StampReady” this means StampReady registered with the Chamber of Commerce in the Netherlands with registration number: 61187496;

### 1.2

“User(s)” means the person or entity that is registered with us to use the Services;

### 1.3

“you” means a User(s) or some other person who visits our Website;

### 1.4

“Subscriber(s)” means a person you contact through our Services, or a person who you might choose to contact at some point in the future through the use of our Services. In other words, a Subscriber is anyone on your Subscriber List or about whom you have given us information;

### 1.5

“Subscriber List(s)” means a list of Subscribers and all associated information related to those Subscribers (for example, email addresses);

### 1.6

“Services” means that we provide an online platform which you may use to create, send, and manage emails;

### 1.7

“Personal Information” means any information that identifies or can be used to identify you or a Subscriber, directly or indirectly, including, but not limited to, first and last name, date of birth, email address, gender, occupation or other demographic information;

### 1.8

“Website” means [www.stampready.net](http://www.stampready.net/);

### 1.9

“Terms” means these Terms and Conditions, our Privacy Policy and our Cookie Policy which define the terms and conditions under which you are allowed to use StampReady, and how we will treat your account while you are a User.

## 2\. Privacy Policy Modifications

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. The most recent version of the Privacy Policy is reflected by the version date located at the bottom of this Privacy Policy. When we change the Privacy Policy in a material manner we will let you know by email to the last email address you gave us. All updates and amendments are effective immediately. We will post any changes here, so be sure to check back periodically. Please note that your continued use of the Website and/or the Services signifies your continuing consent to be bound by this Privacy Policy. 

## 3\. Scope

This Privacy Policy is effective with respect to any data that we have collected, or collect, about and/or from you, according to our Terms.

## 4\. What kind of information do we collect?

  1. Information provided directly by you: StampReady collects information that personally identifies you (“Personal Information”) in some circumstances, for example when you apply for our Services or our Users provide your Personal Information to us so that we can help them communicate with you by email. The types of Personal Information we collect include first and last name, username, contact details, physical address, identification information, company (if applicable), title, information submitted in forms, payment details and enquiry/complaint details. We also collect Personal Information about your interactions and transactions with us, including any through monitoring and recording, any contact we have with you by telephone, email or online for purposes including security, dispute resolution and training. Providing us with such Personal Information you consent to this information being collected, used and disclosed as laid out in our Terms and Conditions and this Privacy Policy.
  2. Information provided by third parties: StampReady may also collect Personal Information from third parties including public sources, our related companies, information service providers and the parties with whom we exchange information as described here. Such as when we send emails to Users, we may track behavior such as who opened the emails and who clicked the links. This allows us to measure the performance of our email campaigns and to improve our features for specific segments of Users.
  3. We also collect and manage information on behalf of our Users, so they can manage their email campaigns. This includes information about our Users’ subscribers such as email addresses, emails received, links accessed (we sometimes track this for Users through our software or provided to us by third parties as mentioned above) and other details entered by Users into our systems, which are subject to our Terms but are not otherwise limited or controlled by us. It is possible that in this respect we could handle sensitive information such as information about professional association membership, political beliefs, health and religion. We do not use this information for our own purposes. We use the data from those emails to create reports about how your email campaign performed and what actions your Subscribers took. Reports are also available to us when we send emails to you, so we may collect and review that information.
  4. We collect, use and disclose your Personal Information to provide, administer, improve and personalize our products and Services, maintain and update our records, manage our relationship with you and our Users and deal with your enquiries and concerns. We may also collect, use and disclose your Personal Information in connection with suspected fraud, misconduct and unlawful activity.
  5. If you are our User, your Personal Information is used to create your personal access to our Services email marketing product, and to contact you in the course of using our Services. Financial information that is collected is used to verify, identity and to bill either you or your company for our Services, as applicable. Demographic and profile data collected by StampReady may be used to tailor our Website or any requested email communications, and to display information that is more relevant to you. StampReady also compiles demographic and product use information, but only as a total, and may make that overall information publicly available. Under no circumstances will StampReady make any Personal Information about an individual User publicly available in this manner.
  6. Your email address is used to only send you information that you have requested as part of your use of our Services, StampReady allows you to elect to receive, or not receive, certain information from StampReady. StampReady adheres strictly to an opt-in email policy. Except as mentioned above, StampReady will not send you unsolicited email information, commercial offers or advertisements. StampReady will not sell, rent, or loan our contact lists or our User’s contact lists (including User data) to any outside firms not involved in the provision of StampReady Services, nor will StampReady use the Subscribers lists of the User for our own marketing purposes. All emails that you have requested will have an option to unsubscribe. Unsubscribe requests are fulfilled within minutes and no further communications will be sent to Users who have stated that they do not wish to receive the specified information.
  7. Cookies and tracking: We and our partners may use various technologies to collect and store information when you use our Services, and this may include using cookies and/or similar tracking technologies on our Website, to analyze trends, administer the Website, track Users’ movements around the Website and gather demographic information about our User base as a whole. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. For more information about our use of cookies and other tracking technologies, as well as how to opt out of the use of cookies, please go to our [Cookie Policy](http://www.stampready.net/terms/cookie-policy/).
  8. Web beacons: We use web beacons on our Websites and in our emails. When we send emails to Users, we may track behavior such as who opened the emails and who clicked the links. This allows us to measure the performance of our email campaigns and to improve our features for specific segments of Users. To do this, we include single pixel gifs, also called web beacons, in emails we send. Web beacons allow us to collect information about when you open the email, your IP address, your browser or email client type, and other similar details. We also include web beacons in the emails we deliver for you. We use the data from those web beacons to create reports about how your email campaign performed and what actions your Subscribers took. Reports are also available to us when we send emails to you, so we may collect and review that information.

## 5\. How do we use and disclose your Personal Information?

We may use and disclose Personal Information only for the following purposes:

  1. Promotional use of our Services: If you use any of our Services and we think you might benefit from using another (new) Service we offer, we may send you an email about that. You can stop receiving our promotional emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in every email we send. In addition, we may use information we collect in order to advertise our Services to you or suggest additional features of our Services that you might consider using. For more information on how we use cookies or other tracking technologies for these purposes, as well as how to opt out of the use of cookies, please see our Cookie Policy [here](http://www.stampready.net/terms/cookie-policy/).
  2. Billing purposes and collection of money for Services provided by us: This includes payment details, sending you emails, invoices, notices, payment reminders, receipts and credit card information. We use third parties for secure credit card transaction processing, and we send billing information to those third parties to process your orders and credit card payments. In case of services requiring payment, we request credit card or other payment account information, which will be used solely for processing payments. Your financial information will not be stored by us. Subject to your prior consent and where necessary for processing future payments, your financial information will be stored in encrypted form on secure servers of PayPal or Stripe, who are beholden to treating your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
  3. Newsletters of Stampready: We may send you newsletters to inform you about temporary or permanent changes to our system and/or Services such as version updates, releases, new features, promotions, campaign notifications and changes to our Terms. Every User can turn these notifications on and off in their account settings except for the latter which will be received by every User.
  4. In order to communicate with our Users and to provide them with support.
  5. To enforce compliance with our Terms and applicable law: We may disclose Personal Information where we, in good faith, deem it appropriate or necessary to prevent violation of our Terms, or our other agreements; take precautions against liability; protect our rights, property, or safety, or those of a partner, any individual or the general public; maintain and protect the security and integrity of our Website and/or Services or infrastructure; protect ourselves and our Website and/or Services from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful uses; investigate and defend ourselves against third party claims or allegations; or assist government regulatory agencies. This may include developing tools and algorithms that help us prevent violations.
  6. To protect the rights and safety of our Users and third parties, as well as our own.
  7. To meet legal and regulatory requirements: We may disclose Personal Information if we have a good-faith belief that doing so is required by a subpoena, warrant, or other judicial or administrative order or otherwise required by law. Including to respond to lawful requests by public authorities, such as national security or law enforcement requirements.
  8. To prosecute and defend a court, arbitration, or similar legal proceeding.
  9. We may exchange your Personal Information with our representatives and with our service providers that assist us with archival, auditing, accounting, User contact, legal, business consulting, banking, payment, delivery, data processing, data analysis, information broking, research, investigation, website or technology services to help us comply with legal, accounting, or security requirements. Third parties to whom we disclose personal information may be located in the United States of America and other countries.
  10. To further develop our Services: In order to provide, upgrade and support our Services it is necessary to use and disclose Personal Information. This may include our use of the information that our Users provide us in order to enable our Users to use the Services to communicate with their Subscribers. Furthermore, it could include for example, gathering information from your use of the Services or visit to our Website and sharing this information with third parties to improve our Services. This might also include sharing your information or the information you provide us about your Subscribers with third parties in order to provide and support our Services or to make certain features of the Services available to you. When we do have to share Personal Information with third parties, we take steps to protect your information by requiring these third parties to enter into a contract with us that requires them to use the Personal Information we transfer to them in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy.
  11. The assets and operations of the business are transferred to another party in the case of a sale, merger, consolidation, liquidation, reorganization, or acquisition. In that event, any acquirer will be subject to our obligations under this Privacy Policy, including your rights to access and choice. We will inform you of the change either by sending you an email or posting a notice on our Website.
  12. Combined Information: We may combine Personal Information with other information we collect or obtain about you (such as information we source from our third party partners), to serve you specifically, such as to deliver a product or service according to your preferences or restrictions, or for advertising or targeting purposes in accordance with this Privacy Policy. When we combine Personal Information with other information in this way, we treat it as, and apply all of the precautions in this Privacy Policy applicable to, Personal Information.

## 6\. Children’s privacy

StampReady does not knowingly collect or solicit any information from anyone under the age of 16 or knowingly allow such persons to register as User. The Service and its content are not directed at children under the age of 16. In the event that we learn that we have collected Personal Information from a child under age 16 without verification of parental or legal representative consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 16, please contact us at [terms@stampready.net](mailto:terms@stampready.net).

## 7\. Personal Information collected by and for our Users

As you use our Services, you may import into our system Personal Information you have collected from your Subscribers or other individuals. We have no direct relationship with your Subscribers or any person other than you, and for that reason, you are responsible for making sure you have the appropriate permission for us to collect and process information about those individuals. Consistent with the uses of Personal Information covered in article 5, we may transfer Personal Information of you or your Subscribers to companies that help us promote, provide, or support our Services or the services of our Users (“Service Providers”). We enter into a contract with the Service Providers to protect the Personal Information and restrict their use of any Personal Information consistent with this Privacy Policy. As part of our Services, we may use and incorporate into features information you have provided, we have collected from you, or we have collected about Subscribers. We may share this information, including Subscriber email addresses, with third parties in line with the approved uses in article 5.

If you are a Subscriber and no longer want to be contacted by one of our Users, please unsubscribe directly from that User’s newsletter or contact the User directly to update or delete your data. If you contact us, we may remove or update your information within a reasonable time and after providing notice to the User of your request.

We will retain Personal Information we process on behalf of our Users for as long as needed to provide our Services or to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, prevent abuse, and enforce our agreements.

## 8\. Third party websites

  1. Social media platforms and widgets. Our Website includes social media features, such as the link to Twitter. These features may collect information about your IP address and which page you are visiting on our Website, and they may set a cookie to make sure the feature functions properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Website. We also maintain presence on social media platform Twitter. Any information, communications, or materials you submit to us via a social media platform is done at your own risk without any expectation of privacy. We are not responsible for the manner of use or misuse of information made available by you and/or other users of these platforms and/or the actions of the platforms themselves at such other websites. Your interactions with those features and platforms are governed by the privacy policies of the companies that provide them.
  2. Links to third party websites. Our Website includes links to other websites, whose privacy practices may be different from ours. If you submit Personal Information to any of those websites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We are not responsible for the manner of use or misuse of information made available by you and/or other users of these websites and/or the actions of the websites themselves at such other websites. We urge you to carefully read the privacy policy of any website you visit.

## 9\. What kind of third parties?

StampReady may disclose Personal Information with the following sort of third parties for the reasons as described in this Privacy Policy.

  1. Service Providers. Occasionally, we share your information with our third party Service Providers, who help us provide and support our Services. For example, if it is necessary to provide you something you have requested, then we may share your and/or your Subscribers’ Personal Information with a Service Provider for that purpose. Just like with the other third parties we work with; we enter into a contract with these third party service providers that requires them to use your Personal Information only for the provision of services to us and in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy. Examples of Service Providers include payment processors, hosting services and content delivery services.

Our Website may contain links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or policies of those websites.

## 10\. Promotional Bundles

We may, from time to time, offer bundles or other promotions on our Websites or through social media and/or third parties (collectively “Our Promotions”). Participation in Our Promotions is completely voluntary. Information requested for entry may include personal contact information such as your name, address, date of birth, phone number, email address, username, and similar details. We use the information you provide to administer Our Promotions. We may also, unless prohibited by the Promotion’s rules or law, use the information provided to communicate with you, or other people you select, about our Services. We may share this information with our Service Providers in line with this Privacy Policy and the terms posted for the promotion.

## 11\. Subscriber Lists

Subscriber Lists can be created in a number of ways, including by importing contacts, such as through csv and/or excel or directly from your email client. Your Subscriber Lists are stored on a secure StampReady server. We do not, under any circumstances, sell your Subscriber Lists. If someone on your Subscriber List complains or contacts us, we might then contact that person. Only authorized employees have access to your Subscriber Lists. You may export (download) your Subscriber Lists from StampReady at any time.

We will use and disclose the information in your Subscriber Lists only for the reasons discussed in article 5. We will not use and disclose the information in your Subscriber Lists to:

  * bill or collect money owed to us;
  * send you system alert messages;
  * communicate with you about your account; or
  * send you informational and promotional content.

If we detect abusive or illegal behavior related to your Subscriber Lists, we may share your Subscriber Lists or portions of it with affected internet service providers or anti-spam organizations.

## 12\. Email campaign content

StampReady takes several measures to protect the privacy and confidentiality of Personal Information in Subscriber Lists. However, StampReady was not built to send confidential information so do not use StampReady in this order.

StampReady may scan the content of your email campaigns to ensure it complies with our [Terms](http://www.stampready.net/terms/terms-and-conditions/) in order to protect against defamatory, inaccurate, abusive, obscene, profane, or threatening material that is racially or ethnically offensive. Our employees may review those particular email campaigns. This benefits all Users who comply with our Terms because it reduces the amount of spam being sent through our servers and helps us maintain a high deliverability.

## COMMUNICATIONS FROM STAMPREADY

## 13\. Notifications

We send all new Users a welcoming email to verify their new account. Established Users will occasionally receive unsubscribe feedback and/or campaign notifications. We present our Users with the option to not receive these types of communications. Users are able to turn these notifications off in their notification settings.

## 14\. Newsletter

If a User wishes to subscribe to our newsletter, we ask for contact information such as name and email address. Established Users will occasionally receive information about the Services, promotions and StampReady updates. We provide a way to opt-out of these communications via the unsubscribe mechanism at the bottom of each email or via the possibility to turn these newsletters off in their account settings.  
From time to time we may make material changes to our Terms and we notify our established Users about these changes by email. Users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. However, these communications are not promotional in any nature.

## 15\. Service Announcements

On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly Service related announcement. For example, if our Service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send our Users an email. Generally, Users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. However, these communications are not promotional in any nature.

## 16\. User Support

We communicate with Users on a regular basis to provide requested Services and in regard to issues relating to their account. We reply via email or social media, in accordance with the User’s wishes.

## SECURITY

## 17\. Notification of Breach of Security

Should there be a security breach that may affect you or anyone on your Subscriber List, then StampReady will notify you as soon as possible and inform you about the measurements that have been taken in reaction thereto. If we determine, and notify you, that you need to forward all or part of that information to anyone on your list(s), you will promptly do so.

## 18\. Maintaining Security

StampReady takes reasonable and appropriate efforts to protect Personal Information from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction, taking into account the risks involved in the processing and the nature of the Personal Information.

StampReady has made a substantial investment in server, database, backup and firewall technologies to protect our information assets. These investments mean that information about the identity and preferences of individual members is strongly protected by StampReady against unauthorized access.

StampReady may process, store and back up its information with the assistance of those providers.

StampReady accounts require a username and password to log in. You must keep your username and password secure, and never disclose it to a third party. Because the information in your Subscriber List is so sensitive, account passwords are encrypted, which means we cannot see your passwords. We cannot resend forgotten passwords either. We will only reset them.

## 19\. Access

In the case of access and correction requests, we will give an individual, either you or a Subscriber, access to any Personal Information we hold about them within 30 days of any request for that information. Individuals may request to access, correct, amend or delete information we hold about them by contacting us by [email](mailto:terms@stampready.net). In case of such a request please provide as with as much details as you can about the particular information you seek, in order to help us locate it.  
Unless it is prohibited by law, we will remove any Personal Information about an individual, either you or a Subscriber, from our servers at your or their request. There is no charge for an individual to access or update their Personal Information. We will comply with any applicable legal requirements to provide reasons if we deny any request for access or correction, or to make a requested note of your desired correction with the information.

## 20\. Location of data storage and transfers

The host servers on which StampReady processes and stores its databases are located exclusively within the European Union.

StampReady will inform you immediately, to the extent we are legally authorized to do so, in case of any application or order originating from an administrative or judicial authority relating to your personal data.

## 21\. Accuracy and Retention of Data

We do our best to keep your data accurate and up to date, to the extent that you provide us with the information we need to do so. If your data changes (for example, if you have a new email address), then you are responsible for notifying us of those changes. Upon request, we will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your Personal Information. We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as long as needed to provide you with our Services. We may also retain and use your information in order to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, prevent abuse, and enforce our Terms.

## 21\. Contact us

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, the information we have collected from you online, the practices of this Website, or you wish to access or correct the Personal Information we hold about you, please contact us at:

### Email:

Last updated: May 15, 2018
